http://www.rochester.anglican.org/resources/privacy-notice/

Diocese of Rochester
Contact us | Search


HomeDioceseArchbishop's visitDay OneDay TwoAnnual Review and AccountsAnnual report and accounts 2017Annual Review and Accounts 2018ArchdeaconsArchdeacon of Bromley & BexleyArchdeacon of RochesterArchdeacon of TonbridgeBishopsThe Bishop of RochesterThe Bishop of TonbridgeBishop's Guidelines & FAQChaplainsChaplainciesAll in a week's workChurch Near YouCommon FundConsultationCoronavirus - Guidance for parishesDiocesan DirectoryElectionsEnvironmentEducation Fixed DatesLife TogetherMothers' UnionPoverty & HopeDiocesan SynodThy Kingdom ComeVacancies and AppointmentsArchdeaconry of Bromley & Bexley Vacancies Archdeaconry of Rochester VacanciesArchdeaconry of Tonbridge VacanciesOther opportunitesLay PositionsLiving in Love and FaithResourcesResourcing & SupportCalled to GrowGrowth Enablers Church Buildings / DACDAC for the Care of ChurchesWhat is a Faculty?How to Petition for FacultyChurch reordering case studiesChurchyardsMeeting dates and guidance notesPublic notices & works to churchesClergy Houses StrategyCommittee & Parish SupportAnglican Communion CovenantBoards, Councils & CommitteesParish RecordsFinanceFormsGuidance NotesStatutory AccountsFinance coursesStatistics for MissionCOVID-19 Emergency Relief FundForms and GuidanceGDPRHuman ResourcesITLegalLand RegistrationTrust & Parish PropertyCircularsGuidance Notes & FormsMissional Property FundPrivacy NoticeSeasonalLentEaster and Holy WeekAdvent and ChristmasSpotlightStewardshipRun a virtual stewardship campaignSurveyorsSerious incident reportingSecurityMissionCovid-19 Community Engagement Social ActionCommunity Engagement and Social ActionCommunity HubsHomelessAddictionsCredit Unions and SchoolbanksMoney worriesDomestic AbuseKnife CrimeMessy ChurchModern SlaveryStop Loan SharksSupporting FamiliesThe Princess ProjectDementiaDiocesan MappingInterfaithCompanion Dioceses Kondoa, TanzaniaMpwapwa, TanzaniaSt Philipâ€™s Theological College EstoniaHarare, ZimbabweDocumentationMinistryCMDCMD Grants InformationCMD CoursesEMDLChildren & CommunionCoursesDiscipleship & Lay Ministry Licensed Lay MinistryMeet the Lay MinistersReadersPastoral AssistantsEvangelistsLicensed Lay Funeral MinistryAnna ChaplaincyIME 4-7Ministerial Development ReviewMusic & LiturgyOrdained MinistryPrayer & IntercessionsIntercessionsPray-ersPraying the WayPrayerMateReligious CommunitiesCompanions of ChristSpiritualityAccompanimentDiocesan Pray-ersQuiet DaysRetreatsSpiritual NetworkThe Prayer Pack Closer courseVocationsIt's Your CallingVocation LinksVocation ResourcesThe Vocations TeamVocations in the BibleNew RevsWomen's MinistrySafeguardingFor childrenFor adultsFor parishesCourses - SafeguardingBasic awareness (C0)Foundation (C1)Leadership 2020/21Safer Recruitment Training Guidance - SafeguardingGuidance - ChildrenGuidance - AdultsGuidance - Domestic abuseGuidance - Safer recruitment / DBSGuidance - Allegations/OffendersGuidance - Policy statementsGuidance - TrainingGuidance -OtherFrequently Asked QuestionsSocial Services Contact DetailsIndependent Safeguarding AuditPast Cases ReviewPast Cases Review - For ParishesUnder 18Anxiety & Mental HealthBereavement & TraumaBreatheChildren and Young People (CYP) FundChild Friendly Church AwardChristmas and AdventNewslettersKEYCOGResources Children and Young PeopleMinistry@Home Family Worship in the HomeKeeping busyKeeping connectedDiocesan Youth CouncilSafeguarding and Child ProtectionYouth and children eventsTraining OpportunitiesEmployed Childrenâ€™s and Youth WorkersGodly PlayImportant Current InformationJob VacanciesCommunicationStyle GuidelinesChurch of England LogosPowerpoint TemplateDiocesan PublicationsE-newsletterArchived e-newslettersTogether magazineGuidancePhotographyOverseas Link VisitsParish MagazineSocial Media GuidelinesWriting News ReleasesOn the RecordFilming in churchesVideo GalleryPhotosOrdinations 2020Christingle service RochedralOrdinations 2019/PriestsOrdinations 2019/ DeaconsRichborough FestivalBromley Schools Festival 2019Church Schools FestivalThy Kingdom ComeLicenced Lay Ministers 2019Children and Youth workersChristingle 50Archbishop's visitOrdinations: Deacons 2018Ordinations: Priests 2018Archdeacon of RochesterPlaces of welcomeBishop Simon's InstallationBromley Church School FestivalChurch Schools Celebration 201Knitted BibleChristmas mobiles 2017Called TogetherOverseas Partnerships 2017The Ven Julie ConaltyBishop James' visits (schools)Ordinations servicesLLM licensing and celebrationsAnna Chaplains (11 April 2017)Churches in The DiocesesMissionBishop of Rochester Bishop of Rochester EventsLatest NewsNews in BriefFaith StoriesWebinarsDigital ChurchStrategyCalled TogetherGrowEnrichResourceOur Conversation; Our Future Chatham Town CentreEbbsfleetKings HillContactContact ArchdeaconsContact BishopsContact Children and Young PeopleContact CommunicationsContact EducationContact MinistryContact MissionContact Mothers' UnionContact Resourcing and SupportContact Safeguarding
Home > Resources
> Privacy Notice
Login
Username:
Password:
Remember me
Forgotten Password
ResourcesResourcing & SupportCalled to GrowChurch Buildings / DACClergy Houses StrategyCommittee & Parish SupportFinanceForms and GuidanceGDPRHuman ResourcesITLegalMissional Property FundPrivacy NoticeSeasonalSpotlightStewardshipSurveyorsSerious incident reportingSecurity
Privacy notice
Our GDPR privacy notice - your personal data
As part of our administrative role within the Church of England, the Diocese of Rochester is committed to providing effective management of personal data and the safeguarding of material which is entirely consistent with the nurturing of a climate of openness and transparency.
Our intention is that we will seek to manage information professionally and intentionally.
To read our full privacy notice, please click here. To view our 'role holder' privacy notice click here.
Here are some key points.
We will ensure that any personal data you share with us is kept up to date, is stored securely and if necessary, destroyed securely.
If you are a ‘role holder’ we process data about you for legal, personnel, administrative and management purposes and to enable us to meet our legal obligations.
You will receive communications from us either because you have consented to do so, or because as a ‘role holder’ we have a legitimate interest to keep you informed of news, resources, events and activities that take place within the diocese, or further afield, that you may be interested in and that will help you fulfil your role.
We will respect your rights as a ‘data subject’ under the new GDPR regulations.
If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by our privacy notice, we will inform you before beginning this new process and explain why.
If you have any questions or concerns about how we use your data, please contact our data controller on: datacontroller@rochester.anglican.org
Our website and cookies
It is important to appreciate that this website provides links to other independent sites, both within the Church of England and elsewhere. This policy applies only to direct accesses to the Anglican Diocese of Rochester website - URLs starting http://www.rochester.anglican.org
Data collected:
As with the vast majority of websites, the Diocese of Rochester automatically logs certain information about every request made of it. This information is used for system administration, for bug tracking, and for producing usage statistics. The logged information will be kept but reviewed periodically.
Relevant subsets of this data may be passed to computer security teams as part of investigations of computer misuse involving this site or other computing equipment within the hosting organisation.
Data may also on occasion be passed to the administrators of other computer systems to enable investigation of problems accessing this site or of system misconfigurations. Otherwise the logged information is not passed to any third party except if required by law. Summary statistics are extracted from this data and some of these may be made publicly available, but those that are do not include information from which individuals could be identified.
Where forms are provided on this site, the pages containing these forms include information on how data submitted on them will be processed and used.
Cookies:
By using this site you agree to cookies being placed on your computer in accordance with the purpose set out below. If you do not wish to accept cookies from this site please either disable cookies or refrain from using this site.
What are cookies?:
Cookies are small pieces of text placed on your computer to recognise you when you return to this website. They can include what pages you visit and other information such as the internet browser you use. “First-party cookies” are the cookies that we set for rochester.anglican.org and “third-party cookies” are cookies on this site that come from different websites. Vimeo and YouTube are examples of third party cookies and their use is detailed below.
Our use of cookies:
The table below outlines cookies which may be set when visiting our site and why they are used.
Cookie
Name
Purpose
More information
Google Analytics
_utma
_utmb
_utmc
_utmz
These cookies are used to collect information how visitors use our site. We use the information
to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous  form, including the number of visitors to the site,
where visitors have come to the site from, and the
pages visited.
www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html
To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit
tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
Content Management System Cookies
ja_home_tpl
ja_blue2_tpl
style
ja_travel_tpl
ja_travel-purple_tpl
ja_bishop_tpl
ja_green2_tpl
ja_travel-maroon_tpl
ja_orange_tpl
ja_red_tpl
d3e67d0faa070e237032cd94df4a92e1
These cookies are set by our content management system, upon arrival to the website. They are not used by the Diocese of Rochester for any purpose and expire within five months.
Vimeo
aka_debug
We use Vimeo to embed videos on our website. Vimeo sets cookies in videos that we embed so they can track the usage of them
These third party cookies adhere to Vimeo’s privacy policy.
YouTube
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE
use_hitbox
We use YouTube to embed videos on our website. YouTube will set the first cookie when visiting a page with an embedded YouTube video and will set the second if you click on the video player, but they will not store personally-identifiable information.
This third-party cookie adhere to YouTube’s  privacy policy.
Refusing to use cookies
You may refuse to use cookies on this website by amending your internet browser settings. For details how to do this covering the majority of browsers, visit AboutCookies.org www.aboutcookies.org. You may experience degraded performance from this website as a result of amending the default option.
Logged data
The following data is automatically logged for each request:
The name or network address of the computer making the request. Note that under some (but not all) circumstances it may be possible to infer from this the identity of the person making the request. Note also that the data recorded may be that of a web proxy rather than that of the originating client.
The date and time of connection.
The HTTP request, which contains the identification of the document requested.
The status code of the request (success or failure etc.).
The number of data bytes sent in response.
The contents of the HTTP Referrer header supplied by the browser.
The content of the HTTP User-Agent header supplied by the browser.
Logging of additional data may be enabled temporarily from time to time for specific purposes.
Access to user data
For the purpose of the UK Data Protection Act 1998, the 'Data Controller' for the processing of any data collected by this site is the Diocese of Rochester and the point of contact for subject access requests is gdpr@rochester.anglican.org
Miscellaneous
This policy may change from time to time.  You should check this policy occasionally to ensure you are aware of the most recent version which will apply each time you access this website.
Useful links
Church of England 
Dioceses in England 
Baptisms 
Weddings 
Funerals 
A Church Near You 
Rochester Cathedral 
This church website is powered by Church Edit | Help
Copyright 2015 Â© The Diocese of Rochester. Registered Office: St Nicholasâ€™ Church, Boley Hill, Rochester, Kent, ME1 1SL. Registered Charity No. 249339
The Rochester Diocesan Society and Board of Finance is a company limited by guarantee. Registered in England No. 140656
